1995-06-18 · Hägerstensvägen 205/1102, 126 53, Hägersten, Sweden

🛮 +46 730 46 98 20 | 🗷 maciej.gumulka@gmail.com | 🎢 www.maciejgumulka.com | 🖸 MaciejoG | 🛅 maciejgumulka

"Interested in developing a career in software in combination with leveraging my leadership skills"



Summary

Electrical engineer with +1 year of professional experience in software and data. Successful leader of agile teams, proven by multiple awards. Graduated with Cum Laude from Innoenergy Double-Degree Master's Program "Energy for Smart Cities", currently working at Northvolt in Sweden. Distinguished by diversified approach thanks to work-experience across three continents. Strong background in building data queries (SQL, Python), machine learning (Matlab, Python), data visualization for decision making. Interested in developing a career in software in combination with leveraging my leadership skills.

Work Experience_

Northvolt Stockholm, Sweden

MANUFACTURING TEST ENGINEER

Mar. 2020 - now

- · Conceptually designed and built a data warehouse for Northvolt's factory including database design (SQL), backend (PHP), frontend (JS, jQuery), reporting dashboards (Power BI) and setting KPIs. The project saves money, time and adds transparency to ongoing production by enabling digital manufacturing
- · Project Manager for BOL & EOL battery testing for the newly-emerging factory lines ensuring fast, reliable production and automated data capture

Northvolt Stockholm, Sweden

TEST AUTOMATION ENGINEER

Sep. 2019 - Mar. 2020

- · Implemented a Machine Learning model for detection of specific type of failures in battery modules. The model aims to replace previously used testing, leading to 40% of time reduction and improving reliability by decreasing the risk of battery failures during onsite operation
- Conducted multiple tests to built the database, acquired and preprocessed data for further use

Northvolt Stockholm, Sweden

SUMMER INTERN

Jun. 2019 - Aug. 2019

· Conceptually designed and built the test procedure to detect battery's State of Charge and charge it to a desired level (later used in the next role)

Land2Plant Stockholm, Sweden

Co-Founder Nov. 2019 - now Co-founded an innovative crowdfunding platform for investors in renewable energy

- · Leader of a team of 4, resulted in winning multiple competitions and securing placement in startup incubators
- · Improved networking and learned how to communicate engineering knowledge to business actors by pitching in front of investors
- Built a financial model of the startup

Empa Duebendorf, Switzerland

INTERN AT URBAN ENERGY SYSTEMS LAB

Feb. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Built a time-series model which simulated equipping a grey-water heat recovery system in a household energy system
- Achieved the system performance prediction over one year and concluded with potential benefits of constructing a physical system before the prototype is built

Education

Double Master Degree in Energy for Smart Cities · EIT - InnoEnergy Dual Degree Program

Leuven & Stockholm

Aug. 2018 - Jul. 2020

- KU LEUVEN, BELGIUM & KTH, SWEDEN · Graduated with 75% cum laude
- Master Thesis: Automated Detection of Wirebonding Failures for Li-Ion Batteries Using Machine Learning
- · Relevant courses: Optimization, Machine Learning and Inductive Interference, Data Mining and Neural Networks, Computer Applications in Power Systems, Communication and Control in Electric Power Systems, Project Management and Leadership
- I designed and built a data analytics model (in R) aimed to help the City Planners of Stockholm in identifying key improvements for energy systems in buildings

BSc in Power Engineering Cracow, Poland

AGH UST Oct. 2014 - Jan. 2018

- Graduated as one of the top 10% students with GPA 3.51
- · Took part in one-semester exchange program at Shibaura Institute of Technilogy in Tokyo, Japan; finished with GPA of 3.9
- Researched over cooling systems during one-month summer internship in Campinas, Brazil

Skills_

Programming Python · Java · Matlab · LabView · C# · SQL · PHP · JavaScript

Analytics Spark · Excel · TensorFlow · Scikit-learn · Relational Databases · Power BI

Domain-specific Battery Industry · SCADA · Power Systems Analysis · Electrical Machines · Renewable Energy

LanguagesEnglish C1 ⋅ German B1 ⋅ Russian B1 ⋅ Polish C2CertificatesPolish Association of Electrical Engineers(Mar 2017)

Solidworks Certified Associate (Jun 2016)
LabView Certified Associate Developer (Jun 2016)
Project Management Principles PMPrin (Apr 2016)

Awards_

2020	2nd place , Copernicus Hackathon - leading software & business team developing product for space industry	Stockholm
2020	2nd place , Innoenergy Entrepreneurship Journey - leading a team developing a fintech startup	Amsterdam
2019	1st place , EPAE Conference - leading a business team presenting startup idea on international competition	Gliwice
2019	3rd place , EDPR University Challange - leading a business team presenting startup idea on global finals	Madrit & Lisbon

Extracurricular Activity

Innovation and Entrepreneurship Journeys by Innoenergy

Spain, Belgium, Netherlands

PARTICIPANT

Aug. 2018 - Jul. 2020

- · Increased networking and creative-thinking skills by solving a business challenge of deicing streets in Belgium using shallow geothermics
- · Strengthened background in public speaking and business-creation by working on my own startup idea during coaching workshops

KU Leuven Swimming Team

Leuven, Belgium

Member

Sep. 2019 - Feb. 2020

• Shared my passion for swimming with fellow colleagues at the university swimming team

IAESTE Cracow, Poland

MEMBER

Sept. 2015 - Jan. 2018

- Designed graphical content for the organization
- · Co-organized recruitment process for new members and workshops between students and companies

"Eco-Energy" Students' Scientific Organization

Cracow, Poland

MEMBER

Sep. 2015 - Jan. 2018

- Designed a solar installation for a racing boat as a member of "AGH Solar Boat" team
- Designed and built an innovative solar cooler (Solar-driven Refrigerator for off-grid Regions), the project received extensive sponsorship and was presented at scientific conference

AGH UST Powerlifting Team

Cracow, Poland

MEMBER

Sep. 2015 - Mar. 2017

• Escaped from daily routine by training with the university powerlifting team